A Guide to the Edward Pendleton Herring papers FA1287
Rockefeller Archive Center
Edward Pendleton Herring papers
1936-1975
Rockefeller Archive Center
Herring, Pendleton
Social Science Research Council
FA1287
8.87 Cubic Feet 8 letter document boxes, 12 legal document boxes, and 1 half-letter document box
Conditions Governing Access
Open for research with select materials restricted as noted. Brittle or damaged items are available at the discretion of RAC. Researchers interested in accessing digital media (floppy disks, CDs, DVDs, etc.) in this collection must use an access surrogate. The original items may not be accessed because of preservation concerns. To request an access surrogate be made, or if you are unsure if there is an access surrogate, please contact an archivist.
When requesting to view audiovisual material, please refer to the Title and the AV Number (example: AV 1916). Researchers are asked to check the "Restrictions" note for each Title. If a Title does not currently have an access copy, please contact a RAC archivist for further instruction.
Biographical / Historical
Born in Baltimore, Maryland on October 27, 1903, E. Pendleton Herring was a political scientist, writer, and foundation executive. He earned an AB in English in 1925 and a PhD in political science in 1928, both from Johns Hopkins University. Herring's dissertation, Group Representation Before Congress, was published in 1929. Upon graduating, Herring served as a faculty member in Harvard University's Department of Government from 1928 to 1947 and as Secretary of Harvard's Graduate School of Public Administration from 1936 to 1947. In this period, he published five books: Public Administration and the Public Interest, Federal Commissioners: A Study of Their Careers and Qualifications, Presidential Leadership: The Political Relations of Congress and the Chief Executive, The Politics of Democracy: American Political Parties in Action, The Impact of War: Our American Democracy under Arms.
From 1940-1944, Herring worked as a part-time consultant to the US Budget Bureau for the Records of War Administration. During World War II, Herring served on advisory committees for the army, navy, and air force. In 1941, Herring took an active role in the organization of the Historical Division of the War Department. From July-September 1945, he worked as a consultant to the Secretary of the Navy's associate, Ferdinand Eberstadt. His work in this position produced the Eberstadt report which led to the National Security Act of 1947, thus creating the Department of Defense, the Joint Chiefs of Staff, the National Security Council, and the Central Intelligence Agency. He was awarded the Navy Citation and Distinguished Civilian Service Award in 1946 for his work with Eberstadt. In 1946, he became director of the United Nations Atomic Energy Group and left Harvard to work for the Carnegie Corporation from 1946 to 1948.
Herring became President of the Social Science Research Council (SSRC) in 1948 and served in that capacity until 1968. Under his governance, the SSRC's annual budget grew from $500,000 when he took the office to more than $2 million when he left. Herring also served as President of the American Political Science Association from 1952-1953. Herring became President of the Woodrow Wilson Foundation in 1962 and served in that role for nearly thirty years. Herring was also an active member of the American Historical Society, the American Philosophical Society in Philadelphia, the Council on Foreign Relations, the American Society for Public Administration, the Cosmos Club, the Century Association in New York, and the Harvard Club in New York.
Arrangement
The Edward Pendleton Herring papers are arranged into two series: 1. Institutional Files 2. General Correspondence
Scope and Contents
The Edward Pendleton Herring papers primarily consist of materials related to Herring's long-time role as president of the Social Science Research Council (SSRC), but also contain reports, correspondence, and clippings connected to his military advisory positions during World War II and his leadership in societies and clubs, including the American Political Science Association, the International Political Science Association, the Comitato per le Scienze Politiche e Sociali (COSPOS), the International Social Science Council, and the Cosmos Club. The institutional files and correspondence reflect Herring's capacity as a foundation executive and academic political science researcher as well as his participation in international projects like Growth of Democracy Abroad (GODA) and the Foreign Area Fellowship Program (FAFP).
Immediate Source of Acquisition
This material was transferred to RAC in 2000 by Edward Pendleton Herring and ingested by RAC as Accession 2000:066.
Social Science Research Council -- History; Social science -- Research -- Developing countries
- Institutional Files, 1936-1975; 1
  - American Council of Learned Societies (ACLS) - Commission on the Humanities, 1958-1964 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - American Council of Learned Societies (ACLS) - Commission on the Humanities, 1955-1963 December (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Coffee House Dinner Discussion Group, 1949-1961 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - International Study Group on Democratic Development, Inc., Dana B. Durand, 1962-1964 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Encyclopedia of the Social Sciences McGraw-Hill Book Company, Inc., Curtis Benjamin & Ed. Booher, 1960 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - International Encyclopedia of the Social Sciences - David L. Sills, 1962-1964 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - American Book Company, 1946-1952 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Franklin Publications, 1958-1963 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Committee for Economic Development - Selection Committee for Committee on Money and Credit; General Files, 1957-1961 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Continental Classroom, 1961-1962 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Committee on Problems of the American Community - Agnes Meyer, 1959-1961 (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - Craig Gordon, 1960-1961 (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - Council for Atomic Age Studies - Columbia University - Christopher Wright, 1959-1965 (Box 2, Folder 13)
  - Education and World Affairs, 1963-1966 (Box 2, Folder 14)
    Scope and Contents
    Four bound pamphlets
  - Johns Hopkins University Annual Roll Call, 1954-1963 (Box 2, Folder 15)
  - Salzburg Seminar in American Studies, Paul Herzog, President, 1965-1968 (Box 2, Folder 16)
  - Harcourt, Brace, and Company, 1948-1954 (Box 2, Folder 17)
  - Human Resources Research Institute - US Air Force Advisory Research Council, 1949-1952 (Box 2, Folder 18)
  - Air University, Maxwell Air Force Base, 3-year term 1967-1970 (Resigned January 16, 1968), 1966-1968 (Box 2, Folder 19)
  - Office of Naval Relations (ONR) Human Relations, 1950 (Box 2, Folder 20)
  - National Military Establishment - Research and Development Board, 1952-1953 (Box 2, Folder 21)
  - National Military Establishment, 1947-1954 (Box 2, Folder 22)
  - National Military Establishment - Operations Research Office, 1951 (Box 2, Folder 23)
  - National Military Establishment - Research and Development Board, Committee on Human Resources, 1951 (Box 2, Folder 24)
  - National Military Establishment - Research Office, 1952-1955 (Box 2, Folder 25)
  - Industrial College of the Armed Forces, 1946-1948 (Box 2, Folder 26)
  - US Air Force - Human Resources Research Institute - Advisory Research Council, 1950 (Box 2, Folder 27)
  - Department of the Navy, 1945-1953 (Box 2, Folder 28)
    Contains citation of Distinguished Civilian Service Award, April 1946
  - US Air Force - Human Resources Research Institute - Advisory Research Council, 1950-1953 (Box 3, Folder 29)
  - US Air Force - Human Resources Research Institute - Advisory Research Council, 1950-1953 (Box 3, Folder 29A)
    Conditions Governing Access
    Restricted material
  - Department of the Army - Special Staff Historical Division - Advisory Committee on Military History, 1946-1953 (Box 3, Folder 30-34)
    Folders contain multiple versions of the Progress Chart: US Army in World War II: Theater Volumes
    Folder 34 contains World War II photographs from Japan
  - Department of the Army - Special Staff Historical Division - Advisory Committee on Military History, 1946-1953 (Box 3, Folder 34A)
  - Department of the Army - Special Staff Historical Division - Advisory Council on Military History - Memos, 1946-1951 (Box 4, Folder 35-35A)
  - Project RAND, 1947-1951 (Box 4, Folder 36)
  - Project RAND, 1947-1951 (Box 4, Folder 36A)
  - American Political Science Association (APSA) - Committee - Congressional Distinguished Service Award, 1959-1963 (Box 4, Folder 37)
    Contains Herring's hand-drawn designs for the award and photos of the ceremony and award to John J. Williams of Delaware
  - American Political Science Association (APSA), 1946-1958 (Box 4, Folder 38)
  - American Political Science Association (APSA) - Committee on Constitutional Revision, 1948-1949 (Box 4, Folder 39)
  - American Political Science Association (APSA) - 1951 Annual Convention, San Francisco, California, 1951 June-August (Box 4, Folder 40)
  - American Political Science Association (APSA) - Regional Political Science Associations, 1951-1953 (Box 4, Folder 41)
  - American Political Science Association (APSA) - Annual Meeting, Washington, DC, 1953 (Box 4, Folder 42)
  - US Atomic Energy Commission, 1947 (Box 4, Folder 43)
  - Psychological Strategy Board, 1952 (Box 4, Folder 44)
  - Department of the Interior - Advisory Committee on American Participation in the United Nations Scientific Conference on the Conservation and Utilization of Resources, 1948-1949 (Box 4, Folder 45)
  - Committee to Make Recommendations to Vice-President Nixon & Dr. Killian ("National Support for Behavioral Science"), 1958 (Box 4, Folder 46)
  - Governmental Research, 1951-1952 (Box 5, Folder 47)
  - Correspondence with Government Officials, 1946-1955 (Box 5, Folder 48)
  - Bureau of the Budget - The United States at War, 1947 (Box 5, Folder 49)
  - Department of the Army, 1946-1947 (Box 5, Folder 50)
  - Department of the Navy - Office of Naval Research (ONR) - Panel on Human Relations, 1950 (Box 5, Folder 51)
  - Department of the Navy - Office of Naval Research (ONR) Panel on Human Relations, 1951 (Box 5, Folder 52)
  - Department of the Navy - Office of Naval Research (ONR) Panel on Human Relations, 1951 (Box 5, Folder 52A)
  - American Political Science Association (APSA) - Miscellaneous, 1952-1956 (Box 5, Folder 53-53A)
    Correspondence and Meeting Minutes
  - American Political Science Association (APSA) - Edward H. Litchfield and Clifford P. Ketzel, 1951-1953 (Box 5, Folder 54)
  - American Political Science Association (APSA) - Committee on Election Statistics, 1952-1953 (Box 5, Folder 55)
  - American Political Science Association (APSA) - Meeting 1959 - Topics, 1961-1968 (Box 5, Folder 56)
  - American Political Science Association (APSA) - Appointment of Executive Director John Gange, 1953 (Box 5, Folder 57)
  - American Political Science Association (APSA) - Edward H. Litchfield - miscellaneous correspondence, 1952-1953 (Box 6, Folder 58)
  - American Political Science Association (APSA) - Executive Committee, 1952-1953 (Box 6, Folder 59)
  - American Political Science Association (APSA) - Committee on Executive Director, 1954 (Box 6, Folder 60)
  - American Political Science Association (APSA) - Committee on Awards - Roosevelt, Wilkie, Wilson, 1952-1953 (Box 6, Folder 61)
  - American Political Science Association (APSA) - Cooperative Research Project on Convention Delegations, 1952-1953 (Box 6, Folder 62)
  - Visits to Institutions - Iowa, Nebraska, Colorado, Denver, Oklahoma, 1949 (Box 6, Folder 63)
  - Visits to Institutions - Chicago, Northwestern, Utah, California, Stanford, UCLA, Southern California, Texas, Tulane, LSU, 1950 (Box 6, Folder 64)
  - University of Alabama, 1947-1950 (Box 6, Folder 65)
  - California Institute of Technology - James Davies Visit, 1963 January 3-4 (Box 6, Folder 66)
  - Carnegie Corporation of New York (CCNY) - Projects and Personnel - Visits to Institutions, 1946-1948 (Box 6, Folder 67)
  - Carnegie Corporation of New York (CCNY) - Commission of Inquiry on Governmental Organization for the Conduct of Foreign Affairs, 1946-1947 (Box 6, Folder 68)
    Contains bound booklet National Organization for International Affairs: An Outline for a Survey of the Federal Government's Machinery for Dealing with Other Nations and With World Organizations, October 1946
  - Columbia University - Institute of War and Peace, 1951-1954 (Box 6, Folder 69)
  - Cornell University, 1950-1965 (Box 6, Folder 70)
  - Cornell University - Advisory Council to the Graduate School of Business and Public Administration, 1954-1961 (Box 6, Folder 71)
  - Harvard University - Graduate School of Public Administration, 1947-1953 (Box 7, Folder 72)
  - Harvard University - Graduate School of Public Administration - Visiting Committee, 1954-1971 (Box 7, Folder 73)
  - Harvard University - Department of Government - Visiting Committee, 1958-1972 (Box 7, Folder 74)
  - Harvard University, 1947-1956 (Box 7, Folder 75)
  - Harvard University - Ad Hoc Advisory Committee - Department of Government Appointments, 1965-1974 (Box 7, Folder 76)
  - Harvard University - Miscellaneous, 1952-1968 (Box 7, Folder 77)
  - Indiana University, 1948-1959 (Box 7, Folder 78)
  - Johns Hopkins University, 1947-1968 (Box 7, Folder 79)
  - Johns Hopkins University - Visiting Committee, 1959-1971 (Box 7, Folder 80)
  - MIT - Ad Hoc Committee on Political Science Doctorate, 1957-1959 (Box 7, Folder 81)
  - MIT - Visiting Committee, 1970-1971 (Box 7, Folder 82)
  - MIT - Visiting Committee For Economics and Social Science, For Political Science, 1961-1971 (Box 7, Folder 83)
  - Michigan State University - Institute of Research on Overseas Programs - National Advisory Panel, 1956-1959 (Box 8, Folder 84)
  - Michigan State University, 1954 (Box 8, Folder 85)
  - University of Michigan, 1946-1964 (Box 8, Folder 86)
  - University of Minnesota, 1946-1959 (Box 8, Folder 87)
  - New School for Social Research - Anniversary Celebration, 1958 (Box 8, Folder 88)
  - University of North Carolina, 1952-1958 (Box 8, Folder 89)
  - Northwestern University, 1948-1959 (Box 8, Folder 90)
  - University of Pennsylvania 75th Anniversary, 1958 (Box 8, Folder 91)
  - University of Pittsburgh, 1955-1957 (Box 8, Folder 92)
  - Princeton University - Advisory Council - Department of Politics, 1948-1967 (Box 8, Folder 93)
  - Princeton University - Visiting Ford Foundation Research Professor, Woodrow Wilson Award Selection Committee, 1957-1970 (Box 8, Folder 94)
  - Princeton University - Woodrow Wilson Centennial Conference on "The Political Executive in the National Government", 1955-1957 (Box 8, Folder 95)
  - Princeton University, 1956-1959 (Box 8, Folder 96)
  - Stanford University - Visit on Behalf of Ford Foundation for its Grant Program, 1964-1965 (Box 8, Folder 97)
  - Wayne State University - Advisory Visit, 1962-1964 (Box 8, Folder 98)
    Contains Part I of Wayne State University's 1962-1963 Annual Report
  - University of Wisconsin, 1947-1966 (Box 8, Folder 99)
    Contains report, "The Impact of Ford Foundation Support at Wisconsin"
  - Yale University, 1948-1957 (Box 8, Folder 100)
  - Yale Ad Hoc Committee Center for Political Administration and International Studies, 1963 March 13-14 (Box 8, Folder 101)
  - Princeton University Press, 1947 (Box 8, Folder 102)
  - Visits to Institutions, 1950-1955 (Box 8, Folder 103)
  - American Academy of Arts and Sciences, Boston, 1949-1966 (Box 9, Folder 104)
  - American Association for the Advancement of Science, 1951-1966 (Box 9, Folder 105)
  - American Philosophical Society, 1948-1970 (Box 9, Folder 106)
  - American Political Science Association (APSA) - Woodrow Wilson Book Award, 1947-1967 (Box 9, Folder 107)
  - The Congressional Distinguished Service Award, 1959-1967 (Box 9, Folder 108)
    Bound booklet published by the American Political Science Association (APSA)
  - American Society for Public Administration, 1947-1964 (Box 9, Folder 109)
  - Association of American University Presses, 1963-1968 (Box 9, Folder 110)
  - The Atlantic Council of the United States, Inc, 1963-1965 (Box 9, Folder 111)
  - Brookings Institution - Advisory Committee, 1952-1953 (Box 9, Folder 112)
  - Brookings Institution, 1949-1965 (Box 9, Folder 113)
  - Brookings Institution Study - US Educational and Cultural Programs Abroad - Frankel; Also Meeting on Political Development, 1961-1965 (Box 9, Folder 114)
  - Carnegie Endowment for International Peace, 1946-1967 (Box 9, Folder 115)
    Contains correspondence with Alger Hiss and notes in connection with his position as president of the Carnegie Endowment for International Peace
  - Foreign Policy Association, 1955-1956 (Box 9, Folder 116)
  - Guggenheim Foundation, 1953-1956 (Box 9, Folder 117)
  - Institute of International Education, 1949-1967 (Box 9, Folder 118)
  - Institute of Public Administration, 1946-1966 (Box 9, Folder 119)
  - International Political Science Association, 1954-1959 (Box 9, Folder 120)
    Contains general information pamphlet about the International Political Science Foundation (1956)
  - League of Women Voters, 1947-1968 (Box 9, Folder 121)
  - League of Women Voters - Survey of Opinion on Government Personnel, 1936 (Box 9, Folder 122)
  - League of Women Voters - Survey of Opinion on Government Personnel - Revisions of Questionnaires and Correspondence, 1936 (Box 9, Folder 123)
  - Markle Foundation, 1951-1967 (Box 10, Folder 124)
  - Milbank Memorial Fund, 1953-1964 (Box 10, Folder 125)
    Contains two bound booklets: Faculty Fellowship Program and Organization Policy and Reform
  - National Academy of Foreign Affairs, 1962-1963 (Box 10, Folder 126)
  - National Academy of Public Administration - Herring elected 1967, 1967-1970 (Box 10, Folder 127)
  - National Science Foundation (NSF) - Divisional Committee for Social Sciences, 1960-1964 (Box 10, Folder 128)
  - Overseas Educational Service (Education and World Affairs, National Academy of Sciences, The American Council on Education) - Herring on Advisory Committee, 1963-1964 (Box 10, Folder 129)
  - Salk Institute, included stops in Los Angeles and Baltimore, 1968 July 21-27 (Box 10, Folder 130)
  - UNESCO, 1949-1960 (Box 10, Folder 131)
  - Century Association, 1946-1969 (Box 10, Folder 132)
  - Century Association Membership Committee, 1949-1966 (Box 10, Folder 133)
  - Cosmos Club, 1963-1970 (Box 10, Folder 134)
  - Cosmos Club, 1946-1962 (Box 11, Folder 135)
  - Council on Foreign Relations - Membership Committee, 1955-1967 (Box 11, Folder 136)
  - Harvard Club Admissions Recommendations, 1951-1967 (Box 11, Folder 137)
  - Public Affairs Committee, 1949-1975 (Box 11, Folder 138)
  - European Trip, 1948 (Box 11, Folder 139)
  - Bermuda Conference, 1971 (Box 11, Folder 140)
  - Canadian Social Science Research Council - Charlottetown, Prince Edward Island (June 9-10, 1964), 1964-1965 (Box 11, Folder 141)
  - European Trip Summer 1958, 1957-1958 (Box 11, Folder 142)
    On behalf of the Carnegie Corporation
  - European Contacts Lists, 1948-1950 (Box 11, Folder 143)
  - Rome-Paris-Geneva-London Trip, 1964 January 3-20 (Box 11, Folder 144)
  - International Social Science Council, Paris, 1954 December 14-16 (Box 11, Folder 145)
  - India Correspondence, 1969-1970 (Box 11, Folder 146)
  - London and the International Social Science Council, Tel Aviv, 1964 April 2-14 (Box 11, Folder 147)
  - Comitato per le Scienze Politiche e Sociali (COSPOS), Italy, Rome, Capri, and Spain, 1967 April (Box 11, Folder 148)
  - Italy Social Science, Olivetti, Palermo, and Taormina, 1964 September 27-October 3 (Box 11, Folder 149)
  - Itineraries UNESCO 5th General Conference, Florence, 1950 May 22-June 8 (Box 11, Folder 150)
  - Third Joint United States-Japan Conference on Cultural and Educational Interchange, Tokyo and Korea, 1966 March 2-13 (Box 11, Folder 151)
  - Korea - After Third United States-Japan Conference on Cultural and Educational Interchange, 1966 March 9-13 (Box 12, Folder 152)
  - Latin American Trip on Social Science, Fulbright, Council on Higher Education in the American Republics (CHEAR), 1962 February 5-March 3 (Box 12, Folder 153)
  - Foreign Area Fellowship Program (FAFP), 1967 November 2-4 (Box 12, Folder 154)
  - International Political Science Association (IPSA) Meeting, Rome, 1958 (Box 12, Folder 155)
  - Inter-American Council in the Social Studies Conference, Mexico City, 1962 July 3-4 (Box 12, Folder 156)
  - Italian Conference Frascati - Political Parties and Political Development, 1964 January (Box 12, Folder 157)
  - Villa Serbelloni - Consensus I and II, Rockefeller Foundation, 1959 (Box 12, Folder 158)
  - Foreign Area Fellowship United States-Latin American Faculty Interchange Program (USLAFIP), Cuernavaca, Merida, Chichen Itza, Mexico, 1964 December 1-11 (Box 12, Folder 159)
  - Nigeria, Carnegie Corporation, 1964 January 1-24 (Box 12, Folder 160)
  - Nigeria, 1959-1960 (Box 12, Folder 161)
    Three postcards - Ibadan Scene East, Ahmed the Sardauna of Sokoto, and Chief S. L. Akintola, Premier of Western Nigeria
  - Ford Foundation - Interview Trip, Poland, Vienna, and Bulgaria, 1967 November-December (Box 12, Folder 162)
  - Ford Foundation - Interviewing, Poland, 1967 June 24-July 3 (Box 12, Folder 163)
  - Ford Foundation - Interviews, Hungary-Vienna (Warsaw Omitted), 1964 May 3-15 (Box 12, Folder 164)
  - Ford Foundation - Poland Trip Necessary Forms, 1959 May 3-25 (Box 12, Folder 165)
  - Itineraries, Turkey, Greece, Milan, 1963 June 24-August 10 (Box 12, Folder 166)
  - International Political Science Association (IPSA) Meeting, Opatija, Yugoslavia, 1959 August 22-September 7 (Box 13, Folder 167)
  - Ford Foundation - Trip to Poland, Zurich, Warsaw, Paris, 1957 May 13-June 9 (Box 13, Folder 168)
  - Growth of Democracy Abroad (GODA) - Japan, 1961-1964 (Box 13, Folder 169)
  - Frankel on Turkey Comments on Growth of Democracy Abroad (GODA), 1960; 1964 (Box 13, Folder 170)
  - Growth of Democracy Abroad (GODA) - Summer Meeting, Italy, 1964 July (Box 13, Folder 171)
  - James Perkins-Pendleton Herring Project - Growth of Democracy Abroad (GODA) Democracy in Transitional Societies, 1960 August (Box 13, Folder 172)
  - Growth of Democracy Abroad (GODA) - Correspondence and Notes, 1960-1964 (Box 13, Folder 173)
  - Democracy (Rockefeller Brothers) Correspondence, 1960-1962 (Box 13, Folder 174)
  - Growth of Democracy Abroad (GODA), 1961-1967 (Box 13, Folder 175)
  - Report on a Study of the Democratic Idea in Mexico, Pendleton Herring, James Perkins and Charles Frankel, 1961 (Box 13, Folder 176)
  - Report on a Study of the Democratic Idea in Japan, Pendleton Herring, James Perkins and Charles Frankel, 1962 (Box 13, Folder 177-178)
  - Social Science Research Council (SSRC), 1973 (Box 14, Folder 179)
    Copies of correspondence concerning Laura Spelman Rockefeller Memorial's grant and other Rockefeller Foundation Funds from 1924-1936 along with "Committee on Political Behavior, 1949-1963, Committee on Governmental and Legal Processes, 1964-1972: A Report on the Activities of the Committees" published by the SSRC in August 1973
  - Social Science Research Council (SSRC), 1972-1975 (Box 14, Folder 180)
    Contains 1974 and 1975 Board of Directors Meeting Minutes, correspondence, and SSRC newsletters
  - Foreign Area Fellowship Program (FAFP), Composite, Screening Committee Instructions, 1969-1970 (Box 14, Folder 181)
  - Foreign Area Fellowship Program (FAFP), 1972-1975 (Box 14, Folder 182)
  - Comitato per le Scienze Politiche e Sociali (COSPOS), 1971-1974 (Box 14, Folder 183)
  - International Social Science Council, 1972-1975 (Box 14, Folder 184)
  - Reece Committee, 1952-1955 (Box 14, Folder 185)
    Contains PH's edits to the Cox questionnaire
  - Reece Committee Mimeographed Material, 1954 (Box 14, Folder 186)